Rinku Solanki Phone +91 9909978175

Email: rinkumsingh2020@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Professional with 10 years of experience in Client Engagement with strong communication skills. Dedicated personnel with quick decision making skills to achieve short term and long term goals meeting deadlines.

Currently working with Maersk Line - The global integrator of container logistics, currently leading the customer services for the biggest region - North India, experience in B2B & B2C.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Maersk Line – Shipping & Logistics		
Title	Assistant Manager / JL- P3	
Location	Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India	
Duration	May 06 2019 – Till Date	
Responsibilities	 The role is to own and manage the customer experiences which are segmented into Care account. On-boarding customers proactively for post sales products and process changes Managing and Ensuring smooth execution of the end-to-end shipment lifecycle. Sole responsible and owner of all customer issues and engage relevant stakeholders when required to facilitate timely and effective solutions Manage / improve day to day process interaction with customers across different channels (case management or Sales-force / Telephony/CTI). Utilize internal IT systems (CODS & MSBI for vessel utilization or cleanups. Commercial intelligence: engage customers in discussions about new business opportunities and competitor/market intelligence. In general, actively seek out and act on continuous improvement opportunities both in relation to customers and internal / external stakeholders. Offering various products to improve business model of customer and expand trade of customer (logistics & solutions) 	

	QX Ltd (KPO)		
Title	Team Leader Operation – Non Voice Process		
Location	Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India		
Duration	Jan 2018 to April 2019		
Responsibilities	 Build positive and productive relationships with various clients for business growth. Promoting company's products and services predicting client's objectives. Responsible for arranging various meetings and discussions with clients, preparing reports, extending our support to stakeholders when needed and handling customer & client escalations to strengthen healthy relationships with clients. To asses individual performance and sharing feedback and coaching to bottom quartile and preparing PIP. Making Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) as per the Service Level Agreements. Monthly Roster Preparation. With constant process modifications, able to highlight credit leakage which helped us in generating revenue for client and this has allowed us to expand team strength and successfully meeting C-Sat as 100%. Improving quality of work with regular client communication for process updates which impact business on a larger scale which as a result keeps my team motivated and intact with our competitors and get more business. Half yearly sampling / auditing to meet company standards and matching with client requirements for Infosec, IT security & money laundering. 		

Vodafone, VISPL(India)		
Title	Team Leader Operation – Web Chat Services & UK Process (customer Care)	
Location	Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India	
Duration	September 2011 till 1 st March to July 2017	
Responsibilities	 Directly responsible for growth and development of my team members. Experience in escalation handling through all source of communication email, chats or calls. Developing skills and grooming team members to promote in different department. Maintaining and improving process (increasing sale volume, Net promoter score high, improving KPI of team) Feedback and coaching to team members for improving quality of work to meet KPI. Weekly team briefing for process updates along with refresher course for major impact on business. SBS Audit to be performed to meet FCR. Preparing score cards and Performance Improvement Plan (PIP) for bottom quartile. Highlighting any alarming situation & taking immediate actions (system issue, technical glitch - software, evacuation drill etc. Meeting clients for process updates and presenting report for further changes on process. Interviewing and hiring suitable candidate for team expansion. Responsible for Induction and further Process training for OJT/ New Joiners. 	

JCJ Locums, QX BPO		
Title	Healthcare Recruitment Consultants & Compliance	
Location	Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India	
Duration	January 2010 – August 2011	
Responsibilities	 Serve clients, identify their needs and provide feedback on success of filling jobs Qualify job specification / salary information and record accurate and comprehensive job description – check info / client requirements in line with key processes and legislation. Updating the jobs in internal database and the software called MWF, creating job description and matching for the suitable candidates simultaneously. Checking with the candidates about their work authorization, getting the documentation completed as per the norms of the clients. Worked with all the levels of grades and specialties including the permanent posts and temporary positions. Applying for the references as per the referee details provided by the candidates. Pre-screen candidates before their interview for suitability and conduct interviews. Providing locums cover on urgent basis, in case of emergency for any requirement of doctors. 	

QUALIFICATIONS

- MBA HR : Symbiosis University Correspondence
- B.Com (Account & Business Management), Gujarat Commerce College March-2005
- **HSC,** Kendriya Vidhyalaya CBSE,March-2002

Personal Details

Gender & DOB	Female, 1st December, 1983
Phone & Email	+91 9909978175 <u>rinkumsingh2020@gmail.com</u>
Permanent Address	Applewoods Township, Ahmedabad, Gujarat- 380058